as we go to cycle three again we can
free this reservation station the
instruction has been dispatched so in
cycle three we have this reservation
station free again don't forget to do
that because you might run out of
reservation stations prematurely
otherwise so in cycle three we are gonna
try to issue this instruction here it's
an ad so we check do we have this type
of reservation station do we have Robin
trees yes we do have both so what we're
gonna do is we're gonna issue this
instruction it's an ad it writes to r3
r3 is now renamed to rob3 we mark here
that we are issuing this ad and we put
this ad here the name of the result is
rob3 because we just put this
instruction here we check our seven and
our eight they are renamed to just the
register file so we can just take those
values of one and two and this
instruction is ready to dispatch which
means it will begin executing the next
cycle it takes only one cycle to execute
so in cycle five is actually gonna try
to write the result and now that we have
successfully renamed this instruction
and so on we don't have anything else to
do in cycle three basically these two
instructions are not gonna write
anything on the broadcast bus yet so
with that we can move on to cycle four
in cycle four the ad begins execution
and at the beginning of cycle four we
already have this entry free because we
have dispatched in the previous cycle so
now we are going to try to issue this
instruction here we have a free
reservation station we have free Rob
entries so it will be able to issue in
cycle four it's gonna take this Rob
entry it will write to r1 so we remember
that we take also a reservation station
we say that we're gonna be broadcasting
Rob for when we do this now what we do
is for this instruction we're going to
look at the right before we update it to
see where do we find our registers that
we're going to use as inputs we are
using r1 and r3 r1 and r3 map - Rob -
and Rob tree so we actually mark here
Rob - and Rob 3 and we don't have values
yet so this instruction actually will
have to wait it will not be able to
dispatch now because it's actually
waiting for this is just Rob - and Rob
tree I'm not writing it out because it
would be too crowded and after we have
read these from the rat we are ready to
update the rat r1 now needs to point to
rob for be careful when you update the
rat you first need to check where do you
find your register inputs and then you
rename for your outputs because if one
of your inputs gets overwritten with
your output you first need to use the
values of the rat before you rename
otherwise you would instruction would be
waiting for its own result which will
never happen
so now r1 it begins to point at Rob four
because that's kind of the latest r1
that we we are going to produce and this
instruction will not be able to execute
yet it's actually going to execute once
both of these operands are ready
so this basically finishes cycle 4 and
we are ready to see what happens in
cycle 5